<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Raphael Silva</title><description>In between the 0s and 1s</description><link>https://peagasilva.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 16:57:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 16:57:32 +0200</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://peagasilva.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://peagasilva.com/posts/2016-04-14-about-learning</guid><title>About learning</title><description>Some thoughts on learning.</description><link>https://peagasilva.com/posts/2016-04-14-about-learning</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 09:41:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>About learning</h1><p>The process of learning is not that easy. And when I say <em>learning</em>, I <strong>do</strong> mean it. I'm not talking about learning on the fly - we've all been there, we all know how that works. I'm talking about learning the subject <em>deeply</em>, focusing on dominating it rather knowing only the basics.</p><p>It's been a while since I started reflecting on the learning process and how most of times we are satisfied with the basics. I mean, if you are willing to learn something, why would you not take some time for it?</p><p>Today I watched the talk <a href="https://realm.io/news/tryswift-daniel-steinberg-blending-cultures/">Blending Cultures: The Best of Functional, Protocol-Oriented, and Object-Oriented Programming</a>, and the following quote took my attention:</p><blockquote><p>"A Swift application is more than just an Objective-C app translated into Swift. We need to embrace the features and philosophy of the Swift language." &mdash; Daniel Steinberg</p></blockquote><p>As I said, we've all been in the <em>learning on the fly</em> position. But what does happen when the urgency for accomplishing something is not in the game anymore? Does the understanding on that matter have to keep low? I guess not.</p><p><a href="https://swift.org">Swift</a> introduced a lot of concepts that were not common among developers who mainly used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Objective-C">Objective-C</a> to program. A lot of <em>changes</em>. Some good, other not so good, but in the end they were all changes. New things to learn, new challenges to face. And challenges are what make us who we are, what change our perception and make us to evolve.</p><p>Are we so afraid of changing that we would rather let something great go away? So afraid of letting go what we have, the comfortable position we are, the level of knowledge we have, just not to start it from the beginning again? I'm pretty sure it should not! A quote I keep in my mind tells a lot about it:</p><blockquote><p>"There are far, far better things ahead than any we leave behind." &mdash; C. S. Lewis</p></blockquote><p>We should always look forward, not looking at things we left behind.</p><p>Right now, I'm adventuring myself on learning <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming">Functional Programming</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reactive_programming">Reactive Programming</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model–view–viewmodel">MVVM</a>. And probably I'll be writing about this process here.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://peagasilva.com/posts/2016-04-12-the-beginning</guid><title>The beginning</title><description>Here we go!</description><link>https://peagasilva.com/posts/2016-04-12-the-beginning</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 09:41:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>The beginning</h1><p>I've always wanted to have a blog. Not one about a specific subject - as I do have <a href="http://www.veganeagora.com">one</a>. Just a blog, a place where I could write and post my thoughts online.</p><p>I "tried" it once, made only one post, and that was it, no more writing. The excuses were always the same: <em>I don't have time</em>, <em>too tired today</em>, <em>I'll write about it tomorrow</em>, and so on. Turns out I did not manage my time properly to take a moment to write about my perspective of life and how I see it through my eyes or anything else I would like to, as I wanted to in first place. Worst than that, I was not allowing myself to breathe at all. And it started to bug me.</p><p>Recently I went to Europe, where I took a moment to reflect about this situation. I realized it's really common in our <em>modern life</em>. We're always busy, always looking for the future and never living the present - when I say <em>we</em>, I mean almost everyone, forgive me about the generalization. We do not allow ourselves to take a moment, to enjoy life at its fullest. We just keep going, keep existing, without really living, without really enjoying life. I'll not go any further on this topic, because I intend to write more about it.</p><p>That being said, I decided to change what did bug me, analyzing the way I prioritize what to do, what to learn, hobbies and so on. I started reflecting more on living rather than only existing.</p><p>This blog is the start of this change. It's <em>the beginning</em>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>