<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raphael Silva</title>
    <description>Make your choice, adventurous Stranger, &lt;br /&gt; strike the bell and bide the danger, &lt;br /&gt; or wonder til it drives you mad &lt;br /&gt; what would have followed if you had. &lt;br /&gt; - C. S. Lewis</description>
    <link>http://www.peagasilva.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.peagasilva.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 10:04:35 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 10:04:35 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to have a blog. Not one about a specific subject - as I do have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.veganeagora.com&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt;. Just a blog, a place where I could write and post my thoughts online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I “tried” it once, made only one post, and that was it, no more writing. The excuses were always the same: &lt;em&gt;I don’t have time&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;too tired today&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;I’ll write about it tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, and so on. Turns out I did not manage my time properly to take a moment to write about my perspective of life and how I see it through my eyes or anything else I would like to, as I wanted in first place. Worst than that, I was not allowing myself to breathe at all. And it started to bug me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I went to Europe, where I took a moment to reflect about this situation. I realized it’s really common in our &lt;em&gt;modern life&lt;/em&gt;. We’re always busy, always looking for the future and never living the present - when I say &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;, I mean almost everyone, forgive me about the generalization. We do not allow ourselves to take a moment, to enjoy life at its fullest. We just keep going, keep existing, without really living, without really enjoying life. I’ll not go any further on this topic, because I intend to write more about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I decided to change what did bug me, analyzing the way I prioritize what to do, what to learn, hobbies and so on. I started reflecting more on living rather than only existing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is the start of this change. It’s &lt;em&gt;the beginning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.peagasilva.com//2016/the-beginning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.peagasilva.com//2016/the-beginning/</guid>
        
        <category>reflection</category>
        
        
        <category>Reflection</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
